Live hacking events, mobile hacking, and
managing a bug bounty program are three
things that I'm very much interested in.
And I'm lucky because my today's guest
has been attending live hacking events
for years, is a great mobile hacker, and
now he manages a bug bounty program.
Enjoy my interview with Joel Margolis.
Hello, Joel. Thank you so much for
joining me in today's podcast. For those
of you who don't know you, first of all,
you should know Joel because you should
be listening to the Critical Thinking
Bug Bounty podcast. But, if some people,
for some reason, don't do it, can you
please introduce yourself a little bit?
Sure, yeah. So, I'm Joel, Joel Margolis,
aka Technogeek. I'm the co-host of the
Critical Thinking Bug Bounty podcast
with Justin, aka Rhino Raider.
So, yeah, you can go find us at the
criticalthinkingpodcast.io
or anywhere where you listen to your
podcast.
Yeah, and right now, are you a full-time
bug bounty hunter? Are you a pentester?
What what are you doing right now? Sure,
yeah. So, I bug bounty as sort of a
part-time thing, and then full-time
during the day, I work at Match Group
where I I manage a team over there, and
I also manage the bug bounty programs.
Yeah. How did you start with
cybersecurity, and and how did you get
to this point?
I think I kind of stumbled into
cybersecurity, to be honest. Um
when I was in high school, which is
you know, I was probably like 16 or so
for those of you outside of the states.
I
I was really into programming and
computers and video games and all that
kind of stuff. It's I sort of taught
myself how to program, and I was writing
this software project that used this
private API for an app. I won't say
which one, but
it's a well-known social media app. And
I had written, you know, this tool. It
was mostly just for like personal use
and for friends and stuff.
But, the tool stopped working one day,
and so I opened up the GitHub page for
this API, and I started looking into it,
and there was this issue that was
ongoing for a while of people who were
saying, "Oh, the the newest version
breaks this. Like, we're having all
sorts of problems. If you you know, if
you want to help out, join this Skype
group."
This was back in the in the days where
Skype was
the sort of the thing. So, I joined the
Skype group, and
that's sort of where where I got
introduced to a bunch of people who were
good at reverse engineering mobile apps.
And this was sort of my like accidental
introduction into security because I
didn't really know what it was at the
time, but I was learning how to, you
know, figure out how APIs work and read
through code and decompile mobile apps
and all these like really nice security
fundamentals from this group. And all I
was trying to do was just figure out how
this API worked so I could get my tool
to work again cuz I didn't really care.
I was just very tar- targeted on this
goal. So, yeah, I
I
started learning how to take apart
mobile apps and figure out how they work
and proxy them and you know, look at the
API requests and turn them into, you
know, code and then use that code to
call the APIs and all that stuff. So,
that was kind of how I how I really got
introduced into into
security.
And I did that for a little while,
and then when I went to college
or university, I ended up again, sort of
accidentally majoring in computing
security
instead of computer science. I I had
originally been planning on going for
computer science, and I didn't find out
until my my orientation day that I was
actually a computing security major.
So,
Orientation day for for cuz we don't
have it in Poland. Yeah, yeah. So, this
was just like the first day of college.
Like, you you know, the first day you
show up on campus. Like, your parents
are dropping you off with all your
stuff,
and you're like finding your dorm room
or whatever, and
and yeah, I got like my badge with my
name, and it said my major on it. It
said computing security. I was like,
"Huh, that's weird.
I don't remember that."
So, you applied for computer science,
but I didn't know you were doing
I did, but maybe I didn't. I I I
honestly don't remember. Like, I
I do remember when I was touring
the college that I had seen they were
doing
one of the one of the clubs at the at
the college. I know I I went to a
Rochester Institute of Technology.
And one of the clubs there was like a
cybersecurity club, and they were they
were presenting, and they were talking
about all these like, you know, how to
hack and, you know, these different
hacking topics, and they were, you know,
giving talks, and there was all these
students sort of just like on their free
time
who were, you know, attending. And I was
like, "Oh, that's that's really cool.
That's really interesting." And I
remember I I sort of walked away that
day thinking, "Oh, wow, you know, I I
could actually I wouldn't mind going to
this college." So, yeah, I feel like,
you know, fate sort of made it all
happen. And yeah, so that's I I stumbled
into security. That was, you know, my
college.
I started working,
you know, doing bug bounty shortly in
college after my first year.
I was doing an internship, and
the intern who sat across from me in the
office was this guy who goes by the
username Cool Boss.
And his name's Pranav. And he
he was a pretty big Facebook bug bounty
hunter at the time. He had found a bunch
of bugs on Facebook. He'd been doing bug
bounty.
And he knew that I was into mobile
security, and he said, "Hey, there's
this CTF coming up. It's a mobile CTF.
Maybe you should check it out." And I
was really into CTFs. CTFs were just
sort of a fun way for me to, you know,
learn different security fundamentals
and test different tools and see these
real-world scenarios. I really enjoyed
them. And so, I was like, "Oh, sure.
Then, you know, that sounds like a fun
thing to do on the weekend. I got, you
know, nothing better to do." And and so,
I I did the CTF. You know, they wanted
you to do these write-ups. I did these
write-ups, whatever. I submitted it. And
then I get an email like a couple weeks
later. They're like, "Hey, you're one of
the finalists for the HackerOne H1702
CTF. Like, you get a free ticket to
Vegas and an invite to our live hacking
event." And I I had no idea what like
any of this was.
I didn't really understand what like bug
bounty was or I wasn't really interested
in it in it at the time, even though he
had told me, you know, like, "I found
these bugs, and they paid me a lot of
money for it." It didn't really click.
And so, I went to Vegas.
You know, that was my first Def Con, and
I kind of just saw it as like, "Oh,
cool. I'm getting to go to Def Con."
Like, it's the security conference that
everybody goes to and whatever.
And then I like showed up at this live
hacking event. I didn't know anybody.
Like, all these hackers are like talking
to me and stuff who I I now know, like,
you know, years later.
And yeah, it was just a a really
So, sort of again, I I feel like I just
sort of fell into it by accident. So,
that that's kind of how I got into bug
bounty. That's how I got into security.
I've been doing it ever since. That was
in, again, 2017. And
you know, I've always sort of been
focused on mobile for my background and
in mobile reversing. And
yeah, that that's kind of how I got into
it. Yeah. Yeah, it is a great crazy
story. Like, for for me, for many of
people watching us, live hacking events
are like the the goal, something we
really want to take part of. And you
seem to just be there and probably
didn't care much about it. It
seems you said you didn't really know
what it was about.
Yeah, yeah. And at the time, they did
this, you know, for a couple years in
the early early times of the live
hacking events where they wanted to try
and find
really talented hackers who weren't
didn't really know what hacking was or
didn't know what bug bounty was
cuz this was still when bug bounty was
also kind of new. And so, one of the
other finalists was it more or less?
This was 2017.
So, this was like the I think the second
live hacking event that HackerOne had
ever done. I think the first one had
been the year before, also in Vegas. It
was much, much smaller. It wasn't at a
big event. It was just like a suite or
something that they'd rented out, and a
couple people had come.
So, this one, like, Andre,
0xACB, he was also one of the
CTF finalists who showed up. And now
he's at all the live hacking events as
well. So, you know, this was a really
good way to source new hackers, people
who didn't really know what hacking was,
but they had like CTF chops. And I've
always seen people who are really good
at Capture the Flag events to have
really good bug bounty skill sets
because they have so much hands-on
experience exploiting bugs, figuring out
how stuff works, that natural curiosity
to just sort of like find the flag or
you know, exploit the bug. Um
You know, that that's always been like a
pretty good indicator. And so, I think
HackerOne tried to capitalize on that.
And you know, it seemed to work at least
a couple times.
Yeah. Yeah, he did. He also said when he
was here
a few months ago, he said that it is a
really good indicator for him when
recruiting people to his company that
people who play CTFs are are really,
really good.
Yeah, absolutely. And and since then,
you're you're hacking Have you been
hacking for the full-time since then?
For for a little period? Or what
happened after the live hacking event?
Yeah. Yeah, so I I started, you know,
sort of like pseudo full-time hacking, I
guess. I was doing a lot of bug bounty
2017, 2018. Come 2019. So, actually at
that live hacking event,
I
I one of the targets was Uber. And they
had these specific challenges, you know,
try and bypass this thing or whatever.
So, I was like, "Oh, that looks fun."
And I was really out of the loop on the
event. So, I focused on that. I bypassed
it. I got to do a show and tell. And so,
the team was like, "Oh, this this kid is
pretty, you know, he seems to know what
he's doing." Fast forward like a year or
two, and I'm applying for internships in
college. I'm looking for my next summer
internship. And one of my friends who
had just graduated, he's working at
Uber. And I was like, "Hey, would you
mind, you know, giving me a referral so
I can, you know, apply for this
internship?" And immediately the the
team accepts me, and I find out later
they knew who I was from that live
hacking event. And so, they were like,
"Oh, yeah. For sure, we want to we want
this guy as our intern." And you know, I
ended up dropping out of college after
my internship. I worked at Uber
full-time for I think about two or two
and a half years.
And then eventually
in December of 2020, I moved over to
Tinder originally. I was working at
Tinder doing security, um, and then
Tinder the Tinder security team moved up
into Match Group, and, um,
now we manage security for all the Match
Group brands, uh, as well as Tinder.
Yeah.
What is in the Match Group apart from
Tinder?
There are a lot of brands inside Match
Group. Probably the big the big ones
that people would probably know are
Tinder, Hinge, Plenty of Fish, uh,
OkCupid, Match.com,
um, Meetic, uh, is one of our
international brands,
um,
in Europe, um, in Asia we have
Hyperconnect and Pairs. Um, so yeah, we
we have a lot of brands sort of all over
the place. Okay, so
are all these around
dating like Tinder cuz I mean
this and Hinge. Yeah, exactly. So, Match
Group their their whole portfolio is
basically online, um, you know, matching
and dating and and, you know, pairing
people together. So, yeah. Yeah, cool.
And these days in regards to to your
being you being a bug bounty hunter not
the program manager, does your schedule,
uh, revolve solely around live hacking
events or do you just hack every single
week? How does it look like?
Yeah, so it it varies a lot for sure.
Um, you know, obviously my job is sort
of my top priority and then everything
else fits in wherever I can. So, I do
try to have like a balance between being
able to, um, to hack and having time to
work. Um, so most of the time, you know,
if I'm at a live hack event, I'm taking
time off, um, basically. So, Okay.
I try not to not to be traveling too
much, um, but, uh, you know, some of
it's unavoidable and for the live
hacking events usually there's a pretty
big incentive, uh, monetarily to, you
know, perform and stuff. So, I try and,
you know, maximize my amount of time
there. Sometimes I'll even take time off
ahead of the events, um, in order to,
you know, prep for those and stuff. But,
yeah, it's, uh, it can definitely be be
a bit tricky to sort of balance the two.
Yeah. In terms of preparation for the
live hacking event, I will attend my
first live hacking event in Vegas this
year. I definitely do not approach it
like you did like not knowing who what
happens. For me it's a big big thing and
I like to, you know, take the best out
of the opportunity I have. So, what are
your tips for me to to prepare for this
and and how should I like plan
everything and and stuff?
Yeah, absolutely. So, what I recommend,
I don't know
I have a guess of probably
which one if you know by now.
Um, so my my guess is,
um,
they'll probably do the scope call when
they open up for submissions or maybe a
little bit before. And so, you can
probably guess what the scope will be.
So, familiarize yourself with that
target just a little bit up front
depending on like how hard you want to
go. I think people set different goals
and expectations for themselves. Some
people want to be like, you know, top
five. Some people just want to find one
bug. Um, so it really sort of depends on
what you want to get out of it. If your
goal is to be top five, then you're
definitely going to want to do a lot
more prep ahead of time. If your goal is
to find one bug, then, you know, don't
go crazy and find some, you know,
product that you can focus in on, I
think. Um, for top five it does require
in these days to have sort of a wide
scope of things as well as the severity
level. So, you need to be finding really
critical things and a bunch of things as
well.
I think just planning out your time and
setting aside time for hacking. Like if
you're going to be going to a live
hacking event, then set at least a week,
um, of dedicated every day 8 to 10 to 12
hours a day hacking just non-stop
hands-on keyboard head down focusing on
the scope for the event, finding
everything that you can, taking lots of
notes.
Um, you know, it's it's it's an event,
right? So, it's, um, it's definitely
sort of like a little bubble that you
got to put yourself into and just like
really get in the zone, um, and you want
to sort of perform the best that you
can. So, uh, it's important to take it
seriously, I think. Um, you know, if you
don't take it seriously, then,
um, you know, you'll sort of you you get
in you get out what you put in. I I see
a lot, um, so, you know, if you don't
put in a lot of effort and you don't put
in a lot of time and, um, you know, you
don't take it super seriously, then, um,
you you probably won't see as good
results. But, definitely like if you put
in the time, you put in the effort, and
you focus in on parts of the target, it
it'll be worth it. The other thing I'd
say is don't put all your eggs in one
basket. Um, I've definitely done this
before where I've spent a ton of time on
one thing. I've said, "Okay, I'm going
to spend all my time focusing on this
one thing. I'm going to find some bugs."
Got nothing.
Um, and so, um,
you know, if you know, there is it is
sort of a gamble and you do have sort of
this like, um,
you know, you don't want to put, you
know, there's a sunk cost, right? So,
you don't want to put too much time in
one thing and sort of, you know, knowing
when to cut your losses and know to say,
"Okay, I think it's time to move on to
the next target or focus on the next
thing or look at some of my notes again
and and maybe I'll put this on on the
back burner for now and then I'll I'll
come back to it later. Um, I think
that's really important as well.
So, in the in the sort of practical, um,
sense there are sort of as far as I know
now there are kind of three phases. The
first is when you know the customer but
you don't officially know the scope.
But, you can hack already on the on the
customer even if you're not sure if the
thing you're hacking on will be in
scope. Then for like 3 weeks before the
event there is the the scope call that
you mentioned and then we know the scope
and then officially the event starts and
then the last part the last phase is the
in-person stage. Is this correct?
Yeah, generally speaking. So, so the way
that it typically works and I'm not 100%
sure, um,
I can I'm not 100% sure about the
Bugcrowd events how they work now cuz
I've been to one in a while. But, at
least generally speaking for HackerOne
events, the way that it works is you get
an invite and at that point they'll tell
you this is the target. Don't tell
anyone
you know, it's in this location. These
are the on-site dates. These are the
full event dates. Um, and the full event
dates are probably going to be maybe a
week or two before the in-person dates
and the in-person dates are going to be
somewhere between three and five or six
days, um, on-site. Time for travel, time
for the event, maybe a day, maybe two
for the event, and then
a day after and then travel home.
When you know the customer, like you
said, you can, you know, do some recon.
You can look at their program. You can
probably infer, you know, Okay, here's
what they own. Maybe if they're a really
large program, which a lot of the time
they are, everything they own is already
in scope. So, you know, okay, either the
event's going to be some new
acquisition,
uh, that they haven't ever tested before
or it's going to be some specific part
of their scope or maybe some new feature
that they haven't, you know, that
they've just released or they want
tested or, you know, they're going to
release or whatever. And then they do a
scope call. During the scope call
they're going to say, "This is the
specific scope for the event. So, what
we want you to focus on." Maybe it's
everything. A lot of the time it's not.
Usually it's like one specific thing or
a couple specific products. Um, they'll
reveal bounty bonuses, which are usually
the big thing. So, either a larger table
as a whole or specific like, you know,
most critical finding on this, first
critical finding on this, that kind of
stuff that, you know, big cash, um,
uh, bonuses that are, you know, good.
Everybody likes that.
Um, and then,
uh,
and then they'll sort of like create a
Slack. They'll invite everybody. They'll
invite the customer. Like everybody gets
in. Like you can start asking questions.
You can start, you know, that maybe
they'll give you test accounts,
whatever.
Um,
and then it's sort of go time. And then
there's basically what's called the
duplicate window, which it used to be
that when a live hacking event kicked
off, it was just a race. And, uh, Fran
Fran actually created this tool called
Bounty Plus, which was like an
automation tool where you would
pre-write all your report all your
reports and then you would like run this
tool at the start of the event and it
would submit all your reports at like it
would format them and and whatever and
would submit them it to HackerOne as
fast as possible so that you could, you
know, beat the dupe window because there
was no dupe window. It was just like
whoever submitted it first got it. Um,
and then you would dupe on them.
So,
there came a point where we had a
discussion. They were like, "Hey, how do
you think we're running events?" And I
remember I was I was in on this
conversation. I was like, "You know, I
think it's kind of crazy that like it
feels so competitive. We should just
have a window where
there's a like duplicate. And I think
Shopify did an event where they were the
first one to trial this. And it was
great because it just removed all of
that like anxiety around like timing and
being the first to click the button when
whatever. It was just like here's 2
weeks. Anybody who finds the same issue,
uh, is going to get duped on each other.
You're all going to split the bounty
evenly, um, among all the reports and
that window closes, you know, a few days
before the event starts so that people
don't have to worry about during travel
and all that kind of stuff. I think the
only exception for that is like
criticals. Um, and even that like maybe
if the same critical came in twice,
maybe it would get split. I'm I'm not
100% sure. I actually don't know. I
don't know if I
been on in that experience. So, um,
I'm sure that somebody does know. But,
um,
yeah, usually crit crits they like try
and fix it as soon as possible. If it
comes in during the dupe window, they
don't leave it open,
um, until, you know, the event start.
But, uh, yeah, and then obviously
everybody travels on-site. There's, uh,
maybe they'll announce a new scope on
the day of the event or whatever. Like,
you know, it's kind of up to the
customer. It really depends a lot of the
time. Sometimes they'll do that
depending on how people are feeling and
how many dupes they're seeing and all
that kind of stuff.
Yeah. Um, and then you'll have one or
two on-site dedicated hacking days.
You're in person. You're with a bunch of
hackers in a in a physical space. You're
with the customer in a physical space.
You can talk with them. You can talk
with the triagers. You can talk with the
people who work at HackerOne. Um, it's,
you know, a very, um, social sort of
thing. And then, um,
you know, you, uh, usually they do some
sort of thing like the day after the
event, uh, like a social like group
event. they'll you know
whatever city we're in where they might
do a tour or something and then the next
day like everybody flies home.
Yeah. Yeah, I can't wait for it. I have
a lot of anxiety over the the
performance, but I just can't wait for
the the last part of it and meeting
everyone.
Don't worry about it, man. It's it's you
know part of it is the connections, but
part of it is also just like the
experience of being there and like you
you got the invite that already like
you're you know
you're through the door, right? So don't
don't worry about it too much and just
you know do your do your thing do your
be your best and what got you there will
will get you through it.
Yeah. What about some some maybe
practical things that you you've done
wrong over some of the events you've
attended like not around hacking
strictly, but maybe mainly about maybe
traveling, planning, taking the the gear
with you.
Yeah, sure for sure. So make sure you've
got power adapters for sure. What I do
is I see you you use notion. I love
notion. I have a notion template and I
have a whole separate like timeline
board for trips and I have it all set up
so that every time I I have a new trip
coming up I create an entry for it and I
say these are the start and end dates
and it goes in you know date order and
it's templated off of a list that I've
curated over the last you know five or
so six seven years of traveling a lot
for life hacking events. And just
traveling a lot in general
and every time I pack I go through this
list I check stuff off I remove anything
that I that I don't need
and then I know okay, I've checked
everything on the list. I have
everything I need. So I have one for you
know my my clothing. I have one for my
electronic stuff. So like chargers,
laptops, power converters, test devices,
extra monitor, headphones, you know,
like all of it just to make sure that
I've got it charged and that I've got it
in the bag and then I'm good to go
and that removes a lot of travel anxiety
for me
just like having a list that I know that
if I've checked everything off then it's
in my bag and I I for sure have it and I
don't have to worry about thinking about
oh [__] did I you know leave that in my
room or did I forget to pack that or
whatever.
So that that's one big thing.
Another thing is
managing your sleep and time zones. So
depending on where you are it can be
pretty rough. I've done some really big
time zone jumps before. I think probably
the biggest one I've done was going from
California to Japan. That's a 16-hour
time difference. So you're you're just
like all over the place don't know what
time it is. You're trying to fall asleep
in the middle of the day and all that
kind of stuff. So melatonin is always
really good
not as necessarily a sleep aid, but just
to help tell your body, hey, it's time
to go to sleep. So you know, like an
hour or two before it's time to go to
bed take some melatonin
and that that seems to help me pretty
well. I also try and sleep on flights um
whenever I can and just
like try and time it so if I'm landing
in the day
try to time it so that I get a little
bit of sleep on the flight so that when
I I quote unquote wake up it's light out
and that helps me reset a little bit,
but um
yeah, packing having a packing list and
trying to manage your sleep and and time
zones are probably the two biggest
things I would say cuz
you're going to feel a lot better
and you're going to be like more present
in your head space as well. So yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, these are good ones. I will
remember about these. You also you
mentioned I think in one of the podcast
an app for changing the time zone. Oh
yeah, I forgot. I actually haven't been
oh man I should have I I've gone on some
trips recently and I did not use it, but
I should. It's called
time shifter. Yeah, so there's this app
called time shifter.
I
I I got to say that I was so hyped about
it and then I I kind of realized that
you know, it's a little bit common
sense. So like once you've used it a
couple times you kind of know like what
not to do. I think the biggest things
where it's kind of nice are when it
tells you when you should and shouldn't
drink caffeine. But basically yeah, this
app time shifter you say, hey, I'm
flying from this city to this city on
this date for these dates and it'll say
okay, like two days in ahead of time
go to bed like two hours later and then
at one day go go to bed three hours
later. And then like the day of like
don't drink any coffee
you know, within these hours and try not
to get any light exposure during these
hours and that kind of stuff and that is
really helpful also for managing jet
lag.
If you have United 1K or above I think
you get it for free otherwise it's it's
not very expensive for the subscription,
but
yeah, yeah, it's pretty I definitely
used I've never been more than four
hours from my my time zone. So
I guess for you being at like almost
every single life hacking event since
you don't need that, but I definitely
do.
Yeah, it's definitely a definitely a lot
and it's a it's a great app. They give
you a couple free free
uses in the beginning I think too. So if
you're you know, you're unsure about it
you can just try it out and see how it
works for you. Yeah, okay, cool. Yeah,
let's let's imagine we are at the life
hacking event already. Let's come back
to hacking a little bit. So what classes
are you focusing on? Are you still
mostly mobile hacker?
Yeah, so I've
recently probably within the last like
year or two I've I've tried to step away
from mobile hacking a little bit just
because
you know, it is my bread and butter, but
it didn't feel like it was really like
challenging me so much and it just felt
very repetitive and I wanted to sort of
you know, learn something new and and
flex areas where I didn't feel as
confident. So I've been trying to get
more into you know, web hacking
more you know, API hacking is sort of
all universal I feel like in terms of
just like looking at how the endpoints
work and and testing parameters and all
that kind of stuff.
But definitely focusing more on like
higher severity bugs. For me usually the
bar for what I choose to report is
pretty high.
I don't like
I'm not the kind of person who will
report like a lower or medium unless I
have to.
You know, if I find something and I'm
like if I find something that I don't
feel is really that severe
99% of the time I'm writing it down as a
gadget and I'm like, okay, let me see if
I can use that later or come back to
that.
I'm not just going to report it and say
you know,
here here's like
you know, email to
user ID or something. Like I'm going to
keep that and and see if I can use that
for some you know, PII leak or or a mass
IDOR or something.
Yeah, now I remember we worked on on a
bug a few months ago which wasn't this
kind of there is a bug, but no one none
of us was like particularly keen on
reporting this I guess it's one of these
things. Yep. Yep, exactly. Yeah.
What typical mobile bugs can have higher
critical severity?
So a lot of the really high ones I've
seen either they'll so like there's sort
of like levels to it, right? So with
mobile there's a native layer and that
can usually be like really really
critical stuff where you're more on the
lines of like code execution or like
even potentially remote code execution
and that usually has to be chained
together. So I think most of the cases
I've seen of that are where you have
some sort of arbitrary file read or
write
where you can create a file on the
system and then that file gets loaded
and executed as like code and then
that's like ultimate impact.
But it's pretty uncommon from what I've
seen. It does happen from time to time
usually actually in the more complex
apps because they're doing such like
funky things
that you know
sorry to interrupt, but talking now
something about like binary exploitation
level or is it still some functionality
you file write file read and then
execute? Yeah, so it kind of bridges the
gap like you do have like once it starts
getting loaded as code or like loaded as
a library or something and then you have
like you know, binary sort of code
execution or
but leading up to that it's probably
some sort of like Android
misconfiguration. So you know, there are
there are a variety of like Android
specific and mobile specific
I'll say and mostly Android is what I
what I work on,
but um
a lot of this stuff applies in different
ways to iOS as well.
So on Android you can often find that
they'll be like a misconfigured file
provider or
some sort of access to the file system
where they're you know, storing a
temporary file and they might be like
reading or writing from it, but they put
it in an insecure place and so another
app can read from that or write to that
and access those files and access that
information. Those types of
vulnerabilities are very Android
specific. Then there's the whole like
you can just never look at the app. You
could just proxy it. You could just
unpin it and you can just look at all
the API requests. You can look at the
back end calls and you could never even
take a peek at any Java code or anything
that's going on inside the app other
than here's the HTTP calls that are
being made
and that's like also totally acceptable.
I think
a lot of people are just doing that sort
of mobile hacking. So if you dive
into like the really like mobile
specific hacking, that's probably where
you're going to
do less in the mobile scene is not
looking at the API endpoints, but
looking at like
what are the activities exposed?
What what JavaScript interfaces exist?
Is there a web view in here? Are there
things that are being exported that
shouldn't be?
You know, are there permissions or a
lack of permissions? That that kind of
stuff. Yeah, I for for Android a lot of
it especially when building like a POC.
I mentioned JavaScript interfaces and
web views.
That's probably like one of the best
scenarios that you can put together is
if you have some way to open a web view
in the app to an arbitrary URL
then you can usually trigger that from
like one click
in the same way that you would from a
web. So like you know, you're on the
your browser and you click a button and
it opens a link through a schema and it
automatically opens that app and then
it's going to open a web view inside the
app to an arbitrary URL and then if that
webview has JavaScript interfaces that
allow it to interact back and forth with
the Java code
then you know there's a variety of
different things. I mean I've seen
really crazy implementations within
JavaScript interfaces of ways to
interact with the app.
You know thing just like action action
handlers or whatever right where you
just say like do this thing
and there's like a list of a ton of
different possibilities
of things that probably would never
actually
be used but they exist and so an
attacker can call those
and do a lot of you know really
privileged tasks or you know do things
that they probably shouldn't be able to
do straight from the JavaScript through
this arbitrary URL.
If it is an ideal where let's say you
have Android activity I think it's
called where you need to have another
app installed on the victim's phone.
What's usually the risk of it
considering let's say the impact of the
bug is is you can take over an account.
What how do companies look at the attack
scenario where the attacker has to have
an app installed on victim's phone?
Yeah so I think even from a CVSS level
your attack vector automatically is
basically local or physical like
probably physical right cuz local would
imply local network. So it's a really
really difficult
attack scenario to justify I think. It's
one of those things that has to be sort
of looked at a little bit differently
than most types of bugs because if you
ignore the context of this is you know a
mobile app on a mobile phone then you
know there's lots of different ways that
mobile phones can be compromised and
stuff then you can say you know this is
almost impossible to exploit but I think
it's it's getting more and more common
that you know people's devices are able
to be exploited you know there's
people are downloading apps from the
Play Store that have malware on them
people are you know side loading apps
for other functionality and they don't
know where that's coming from and
they're they're just sort of blindly
installing it. So these things do happen
I would love to see some sort of like
data
maybe from like Google that's talks a
little bit about
um
you know what the actual risk is of this
and like how many people are doing this
and and what the the risk like
profile sort of looks like because I
think for programs it's really difficult
to determine how to handle those things
and every program is going to be a
little bit different in terms of like
what their risk scenario looks like and
what the the accepted risk is for them.
And so they might just say okay you know
if you have to install another app on
the phone to exploit this like
we're willing to accept that risk or you
know maybe they'll take it
you know a little more seriously but it
can be really difficult to to protect
against that kind of stuff so
I think probably some sort of guidance
from like Google or you know cuz they
would probably have the most information
but some sort of guidance on like you
know how realistic these sort of
exploits are and how often they're
happening would help shape how how it
should affect severity because
if you sort of say okay like this is the
mitigation level now let's just look at
the exploit it's an RCE or whatever but
you have to have an app on the phone all
right well should it be a medium or
should it be a high right like
but I think still calling it a critical
can be really challenging because of
that mitigating factor
and that like requirement of that level
of user interaction or that level of
user exploitation in order to fully
exploit it.
Yeah and also
would it probably be useful to have a
CVSS for mobile apps maybe created by
somebody with a lot of data because you
mentioned that the physical but if you
if you set attack scenario to physical
the
then you're sort of on par with somebody
actually plugging the the USB into the
your device and potentially you know
jailbreaking or rooting the device
physically. I think it's it's still more
likely that you know we have hundreds of
apps apps installed it's more way more
likely that one of them wants to do
something malicious rather than you know
somebody having access to to our phone
physically.
Right like I think nowadays like
honestly the most likely scenario is
that some app developer has their
credentials in Telegram list and
somebody logs in and compromises that
app and then they upload a malicious
version of the app that gets distributed
it goes through Play Store protect it
sneaks through or whatever and they
infect a bunch of people who have
already installed this app and then the
next time they open it
it does something malicious and that's
a really tricky risk scenario because
that could be happening right now for
all you know
and you know
a lot of programs would say you know
okay this doesn't matter but then if it
was happening to them like of course
they take it seriously so
it's really just you know how likely is
it and
figuring out how to weigh that with like
reality versus like theory is it can be
really challenging I think.
Yeah I would definitely put this if I
would write a report about it I would
list different scenarios I would
definitely not think about a developer
being compromised it is definitely
likely and it's definitely something I
would put now in the report.
If I were a mobile hacker but I'm not
really
into these things yet for us a little
bit more beginner how can we utilize
mobile apps maybe to like extract HTTP
endpoints get some information about the
target?
Yeah absolutely so there's a couple
really good tools
Jadx is probably the main tool that I
would recommend to most people Jadx has
a Jadx GUI you know it's literally just
like a jar file you run it it opens up
an app it says hey
drag and drop your APK in you drag it in
it lets you explore the the decompiled
Java code very very straightforward it
has searching has jump to definition it
has a lot of
you know sort of IDE almost like the
developer sort of tools where you can
jump to things and you can I think you
can even create Frida scripts from it
automatically and stuff there's there's
all sorts of really good features in
there I use that as my main decompiler I
use the CLI version but it's the same
thing
and yeah that's a really great tool I
think for for a lot of people if you're
just wanting to like look at how the APK
works and and look at the code and
figure out how that works at the low
level Jadx is great
then for proxying and stuff so I have I
have a Frida script that I published on
the Frida
code share.
I'll send a link to you I don't know if
you have a way to
share links and stuff
description. But this is generally what
I you know this is my go-to I try to
update it if I ever make updates to it
on my local version but generally this
is what I use like 99% of the time for
unpinning SSL on apps this catches a lot
of the really big SSL pinning methods
okay HTTP the built-in
Android ones the trust managers like all
sorts of things
um
and then for cases where it doesn't
that's when you have to get a little
more of a spoke and often that's when
you'll have to dig into the code as well
to try and figure out how they're doing
the pinning maybe they've done it with a
generic library but they've obfuscated
the class names so it's not getting
hooked
you know it can vary a lot we're
actually doing a a master class with the
critical thinkers on the critical
thinking bug bounty Discord next week
specifically around this topic of SSL
pinning and how to get around those
really tricky edge cases cuz there was a
really great example that I was looking
at just a couple weeks ago where
somebody was like hey I tried your
script didn't work and they nerdsniped
me and I spent a bunch of time and I was
like hmm this is really interesting so
yeah it's it's definitely one of those
one of those things can that can be kind
of tricky but I think like most of the
time this script works really well
and unless they've done something
special to you know change up how
they're doing cert pinning this works
out of the box a lot of the time and
then you can just proxy it you know
install your Burp Suite on the device
there's a ton of tutorials out there on
how to install the certificate on the
device and you just install it trust it
and then you just proxy through for
proxying I actually have there's a blog
post that I made many years ago for
HackerOne I believe
which was like talking about how to get
into like the interest of mobile hacking
it was a lot of it was just like general
knowledge and stuff but
probably the most useful things were
some of the tips that I put at the end
and one of those things is that you can
proxy over USB
with ADB so if you don't know you know
ADB is the Android debug bridge and it's
generally how you can you know open a
shell on your device or you can push and
pull files from it or you can run
commands on the device and all these
types of stuff
and usually it's by plugging in with USB
you can do it wirelessly actually but
obviously for this case I would
recommend just you know you you want to
take advantage of the fact that it's
over USB so a lot of the times say
you're hacking in a hotel
there's client isolation so you can't
proxy from your device to your laptop
even if you're on the same subnet even
if you have the IP
you know you can't talk between clients
well with ADB proxy you can
so what you do is you ADB reverse and
you give it you know TCP port 80 TCP
port 8080 and that makes a tunnel on the
device from port 8080 on the device to
port 8080 on your host and it all goes
over the USB
over the cable
and then you can just you know proxy to
local host port 8080 on your device and
all that traffic gets funneled through
ADB to your Burp Suite and on your Burp
Suite you just keep listening on local
host 8080 you don't have to listen on
any new interfaces or anything like that
and and just works out of the box so
yeah that's what like one of my real
favorite tips uh is
using ADB proxy.
That's something that I do all the time.
It works the same way with emulators,
too, even though there's no physical
cable. It's just like you can proxy from
your emulator to your host with ADB. You
don't have to worry about the different
virtual networks and stuff that it
creates for the emulator. It's just, you
know, 127.
What else?
Oh, root AVD is this project. It's a
great great tool. I believe it lives on
Git GitLab now. I'll send you a link to
it, as well.
Yeah, send me a link
later.
Yeah, but that's it's a tool for
rooting the emulators that you would
create with Android Studio. So,
especially nowadays with the
the ARM 64 chips in the new Macs and
there's even laptops now with ARM 64
chips.
You know, it's definitely way easier to
run emulators that are running native
ARM 64 on the host than it is to try and
emulate that. Or, if you're running on
like an x86 host, then your emulator
also is going to run an x86 for the most
performant version. And a lot of apps
don't have libraries for x86 or they're
not cross-compiled for all
architectures, so they might not even be
downloadable. They might not work at all
on the emulator. So, it's just a whole
thing. If you're running native ARM 64,
it's really great.
And so, I just use the default out of
the box Android Studio emulator.
And you can use this tool to root those
images cuz a lot of times it'll say, you
know, this is a production build, so you
can't run ADB root.
And you don't know what to do from
there. Well, this is what you do from
there. You you use this and it roots it
like it was a physical device. It roots
the system image. It like installs
Magisk. It installs the SU APK. And then
you can run, you know, SU basically like
Super SU or whatever, right? And you
just run like SU and you approve it just
like as if you rooted a physical Android
device.
And then you can still use the Play
Store. You can still use all that kind
of stuff.
And it's it's a great great tool. Yeah,
I use it all the time.
Do you do you have a physical device as
well or you don't think it's necessary?
Yeah, I do. So,
for certain things,
Bluetooth and anything you're testing
with Bluetooth, that's definitely a big
blocker for emulators because you can't
emulate Bluetooth. And I think even on
Linux you can't do Bluetooth
pass-through to the emulator.
I know you can't on Mac and PC at least
that that I've been able to figure out.
So, anything that tests with Bluetooth,
usually it won't even let you download
it from the Play Store.
And so, that's where physical devices
are really great.
You know, just at least having it to
download the APK or to test with
you know,
there are definitely just instances
where having a physical device is
better. Anytime a type of emulator
detection, bypassing it can sometimes
just really be a pain. And so, just
using a physical device for that, as
well,
can be really nice. So, yeah, I have a
physical
Android device. I have a physical iOS
device.
The iOS device is still running like iOS
14 or something cuz it's jailbroken. And
I don't want to upgrade it. And
you know, that's that's great, but I
will have to eventually upgrade it, I
think. Yeah, I remember the pain of like
being so cautious to not update the the
version of iOS when we did some pen The
problem is now that there are apps that
require like iOS like 15 or above. And I
can't install them. And I can't I can't
test them because it's like it's too
old. But if I upgrade, then I lose my
jailbreak. So,
I'm in a little bit of a
a pickle, but
that's also part of one of the reasons
why why I really like Android testing is
you don't have these sort of hurdles for
like you don't have to have a jailbroken
device or some sort of like other hacky
method of like running the app or like
using Corellium or whatever. Like
you just get a you just root your
Android, you know, and you just install
it.
cases do you actually test iOS instead
of Android?
Usually,
if there's only an iOS app or if I'm
doing a pen test that requires iOS
testing,
I'll do it if it's necessary, but also
I'll usually say like I prefer doing the
Android side, but I can also do the iOS.
Yeah. When we used to do some pen
testing, it was always almost always
just the same findings in Android and
iOS. Just iOS would take so much longer
to test. And sometimes the the 5 days of
a mobile pen test, 4 days was preparing,
bypassing the jailbreak detection,
bypassing the SSL pinning. It's probably
the only piece of like binary hacking
I've ever done in my life to to do some
bypass
of of SSL. And also, you mentioned there
will be a masterclass in the Critical
Thinking's Discord. For people that are
listening to this, it's already
it's already in the past. But if you're
a Critical Thinking member, it is
definitely available on the exclusive
content channel. It's called
Correct. So, you can go and take a look.
And yeah, it is definitely for me one of
the things that that sort of
still keeps me from doing any any mobile
hacking is is all the things you had to
do to even start testing because it's
yeah, it's very time-consuming. Yeah,
absolutely. Yeah. Yeah, like you said,
we record all of the masterclasses and
we post them in that channel. So,
I actually did a mobile
like setup and intro like setting up
Frida and getting all of that working. I
think I even covered a couple of the
tools that I just talked about in that.
And so, that also should be recorded in
in there if you're interested.
Yeah, you can just go to
ctbb.show/discord
and that'll take you right to right to
the Discord.
Yeah. And the the other sort of side of
of this is in bug bounty we all have to
somehow differentiate from from the
others. And often the things that are
hard and time time-consuming are exactly
this cuz I think in every single
interview when mobile hacking is
mentioned, and no matter if it's an
interview from 5 years ago, 2 years ago,
now,
either you or somebody else would say
that still there's not many people doing
mobile hacking. It's still true in 2024.
Oh, yeah, absolutely. There there are
very few people. Like I am surprised to
see like
no like I'm waiting to see like you
know, a slew of new mobile hackers come
up, but it's still very very like, you
know, niche. Very few people get into
it. It's a super high barrier for entry
for some reason. And it seems to be
mostly existing hackers that already
know like what they're doing like
saying, oh, I want to start doing mobile
hacking, as well.
Not just people being like, oh, I I
like, you know, pulling apart mobile
apps like like I was when I was 16.
Yeah.
Yeah, you have very very unique path
that you just started with the mobile
hacking stuff. And this got you even
more unique path with the life hacking
event and so on and so forth, but
Yeah, exactly. Yeah. I think there's
probably a a decent amount of like
uncovered like
untested attack surface on iOS stuff
because of this barrier to entry. Like
you said, like because it's so hard and
because there's this high bar to even
get into it,
that automatically is going to stop so
many people's eyes from looking at it.
And so, I wouldn't be surprised if
there's some, you know, really cool
iOS-specific attacks and all sorts of
things that just haven't been tested
because it's, you know, nobody's looking
at it.
Yeah. And also, one of the question
about mobile, do you have some sort of
automation around them to, I don't know,
scan for vulnerabilities or scan for
secrets or
Yeah, a little bit. So, I have some
like, you know,
fancy grep or whatever you want to call
it for like
looking through strings and stuff. I
also have a couple little shortcuts, you
know, bash scripts and stuff that I use
to basically just like look at the XML.
One of them I think I actually have
published on my GitHub
for parsing the Android manifest XML.
I'll try and find that and link that to
you, as well.
But
I usually run that and it just will
print out all the schemas, all the
activities, anything that's exported.
There's another great tool called Medusa
by Chopin with a zero. I'll send that
one to you there.
That one's also really a great tool for
just sort of like getting attack surface
and exploring the APK that utilizes
Frida under under the hood. That was
written by
another mobile hacker.
I don't know if they want to be outed,
so I won't I won't say what their
username is, but
yeah, they're they're a great mobile
hacker. And um
this this tool is made by them. So, they
they do a lot of really cool stuff.
But uh
yeah, I mean, it's it's definitely kind
of tricky to do automation on the mobile
level unless you get really in the weeds
because it's a lot of code analysis a
lot of the time. So, yeah, I do have
some automation mostly for finding
attack surface and just like making
things a little bit easier to know where
to start looking. But then a lot of it
is manual manual sort of tooling. A lot
of it's just like aliases to other
commands.
Yeah. Okay. Let's let's go to the to the
next section cuz apart from being a
hacker, you're also now a program
manager, which means you have the unique
perspective of of seeing both sides of
bug bounty.
And my first question is, when working
with hunters, what are some, let's say,
green flags that that make you think,
you know, oh, I'd like to keep this
hunter hunting on my program cuz he
finds some good stuff.
Yeah, so I think a lot of the time
sort of capturing the attention of a
hacker can be really challenging.
Part of it is having it a scope that
keeps them engaged. And part of it is
also just having a team that appreciates
them and keeps them engaged. So,
when they're putting in
good solid research. And what I mean
what I mean by that is like
it's not necessarily just like fluff or
it's not just like, here's a bunch of
findings. It's impactful findings and it
shows that they there's like a really
good thought process behind it. I think
for me, especially as a hacker, I can
tell pretty quickly when somebody has
just like run some automation and they,
you know, have submitted this report 500
times before.
And there's no real depth to it versus
some sort of thing that sort of walks me
through like, you know, how they got
here or
you know, the things that they had to
bypass or um
you know,
certain maybe bespoke research that they
did for that program.
Um you know, it's not always the case
for sure where each program has
something that would allow you to do
that, but I think um when you can sort
of approach your bugs from the
perspective of the security team and you
can sort of justify the security impact
and you can show demonstrate, you know,
sort of like a just
you know, you you want to be able to
phrase things in a way that the security
team understands it. So, I think sort of
targeting your audience is really
important and understanding like the
people who are looking at this are
looking at it from a what's the impact,
what's the security impact state. And if
you can show impact really well instead
of just saying here's a bug, um that
also really goes a long way, I think.
Um so, yeah, those are probably the
types of people I want who are, you
know, spending a lot of time really
research
um and, you know, they they understand
sort of
the perspective both the hacker and the
security team at the company.
What's what is then the opposite? What
are hunters What are things that hunters
keep doing that for you as a as a
company are not bringing you much value
and instead maybe the it wastes your
time.
Sure. Um
I think like
one big thing that I see a lot is
frequently asking for updates.
Um you know, sometimes the program may
like things may have slipped through,
but generally speaking,
um you know, the way that that things
work, I think a lot of hackers don't
really have the understanding of like
what goes on behind the scenes when the
report comes in. So, when
Can we maybe go go through the whole
life cycle of what happens with the
report from the submission to the to the
end of it?
Yeah, sure. So, I'll I'll speak about it
from sort of like a
the side of like we use HackerOne
triage. So, um that modifies the process
a little bit, but basically a report
comes in.
We
will often get a notification about it
and depending on what it is, we may or
may not jump on it immediately if it's
something that's like a P0, but most of
the time we let HackerOne triage test
it, make sure it's valid, make sure it's
in scope, make sure it's reproducible,
rewrite it into a well-formatted report,
and then it gets submitted to our team
for review.
And at that point we decide um if this
is something that is in scope for us and
is something that we're going to fix. Uh
you know, it's not informative, it's not
an internal dupe, it's not um you know,
anything else. Um and at that point if
it is, then we will triage it and we'll
create a ticket internally with the
engineering team to get that work fixed.
Then it's basically sort of out of our
hands in terms of like we can push for
it to get fixed, we can provide them
support, but we can't fix it ourselves
um cuz that's not our job. Um and so,
it's really on the engineering team to
um prioritize it. They have SLAs, they
have their own work going on and stuff.
So,
you know, basically it's waiting for
that to get fixed. And then once it does
get fixed, uh you know, we'll verify
that it's been properly fixed, that
there's no, you know, bypasses or
anything, we'll send it back to the
researcher and it gets resolved. At some
point between when it gets triage and
when it gets resolved, we aim to pay out
the bounty as soon as possible. Um
generally we can do that if we can fully
identify the impact. Sometimes we can't
right away. Um you know, sometimes we
have some behavior and we're not really
sure like what the full impact is
um or if it's something that, you know,
could have a wider impact or affect more
people or whatever. So, we can't really
identify, you know, what payout we
should be giving it at that time. Um and
then once we find out more info, then we
can say, "Okay, this is the actual
severity." Maybe we'll adjust the
severity after triage. Um and then we'll
we try to pay it out as soon as we can.
Um
but uh yeah, that that's generally the
life cycle is, you know,
incoming report validation, decide if
it's something that we accept, send it
to get fixed, wait for it to get fixed,
verify it's fixed,
close it.
So, what do you think is reasonable time
to wait for updates?
Um Apart from it depends, which I know
is the only true answer.
Yeah. Yeah, it really does depend, but
um I think, you know, probably like
at least a month. I don't know. It it
depends on what stage it's in, right?
So, if it's after triage and, you know,
it seems to you the researcher that the
impact is pretty straightforward, you
can always ask like, "Hey team, I was
just curious
uh you know, if you pay on triage or if,
you know, you'd be willing to pay out
the bounty on this before it gets
resolved. Let me know if there's
anything I can do to help clarify the
impact or whatever." Like, you know,
just
be be calm and courteous about it.
Sometimes they might not pay until
resolution. I think most programs try
and pay as soon as possible, but um
generally if they haven't paid, it's
like one of a few reasons would be my my
general guess is either they're
in the process of filling their bounty
budget, which probably happens more
often than you might realize. So,
they're just like stuck with no money
and they can't really pay anything yet
until like finance like subs are getting
their feet. Um
or they
uh haven't had a meeting to do the
payouts yet um cuz a lot of times the
teams will do like scheduled meetings
like maybe once a week or once every 2
weeks where they pay out a bunch of
things at the same time.
And they can discuss all the reports or
maybe it slipped through the cracks or
they don't know the impact yet. So,
sometimes it stuff does slip through the
cracks, right? And so, that's why I
wouldn't say like don't follow up at
all, but I think if you're following up
every 4 days or every like week, um
that is like, you know, at a certain
especially if they've already if they
paid it already, then like I personally
I wouldn't even be following up. Like I
Why would you why would they not bother?
Well, right. And so, that's the thing is
like a lot of the times even, you know,
there will be researchers who um you
know, something's been paid and it's
triage and they're like, "Hey, any
updates on this?" And it's like, why
like
what more do you want? Like it's just
the reputation, I guess. Um but it can
be very exhausting for the program, I
think, to have to um continually respond
to that and just try and like reiterate
the same points like, you know, when
it's resolved cuz a lot of times, like I
said, when engineering fixes it, the
security team finds out that it's been
fixed and then they go and verify it and
then it gets pushed back to the
researcher as a resolution or
potentially a retest depending on the
situation. And so, I think most of the
time it's not that
that it's the ball's been dropped, it's
that there's no there's nothing to
update on, right? The team's still
working on fixing it, they have other
priorities, like whatever it is, and uh
it just isn't done yet. And so, all
you're going to get back from the
security team is, "Nope, we're still
working on it. Like, we'll keep you
posted when there's another update."
Right? Like, and that's,
you know,
there you can send that same message
like 10 times, but it's not going to
change uh you know, the outcome. So,
um I think,
you know, following up over and over
again can be um
destructive in the sense that it can
leave sort of a negative uh or a bad
taste in the mouth of the security team
when you're working with that
researcher. And then the next report
comes in and they go, "Oh man, it's it's
this uh this researcher who pings us
every week about, you know, the status
of this bug." And, you know, that that's
not a great experience. So, I think, you
know, just being respectful and um
trying to be aware of the communications
back and forth like just remember
there's a real the other side of, you
know, there's a real human being who's
at that security team who's writing that
message back to you back and forth. Um
it's not a robot. So,
um you know, just
uh keep that in mind and
uh you know, just communicate openly and
transparently is is always what I ask.
Like, there's no such thing as a stupid
question. So, if you're like, "Hey, do
you want me to stop pinging you?" Like,
I bet programs would love if you just
asked that if you feel like you're doing
too much. And they'll say like, "Yeah,
we'll let you know when it's done." You
know, like it's uh you know, th- those
types of communications are great to
see. So, yeah.
Yeah, and also the the the thing about
pinging somebody after the payout is is
interesting. I would never think it I I
now I think about it maybe
it changed my mindset when I was
starting back bounty. I had still the
mindset of being a I was a pentester
before, so I worked in the company, so I
sort of cared more about the security
posture of the whole company cuz I was
also partially responsible for this.
But in in back bounty, after some time,
my mindset shifted to I'm here to let
the company know about the bug and
that's the end of my responsibility. If
they make the business decision, it is
not a vulnerability, it is not my
problem. My problem ends with letting
them know it's there and my concern is
my payout. So, that's pretty much the
end of it. That's that's one thing I
see. And the other also is uh just the
metrics of a program. Like right now I
have a program that has
that says on HackerOne it usually takes
about 2 months to resolve the bug.
And now we are talking I it's been to
about 2 months more than 2 months since
it's been it's been triaged and I still
haven't pinged them because that's
exactly what I signed up for. I signed
up for waiting 2 months for the payout.
So,
surely I would ask for it if the the
magic would say like a week, 2 weeks,
even a month, I would already ping them.
But with with 2 months, I'm like, that's
that's what what I was promised to Yeah.
To wait for
Yeah, absolutely. Yeah, yeah. And I
think like those metrics like they can
also be a little tricky to read cuz
sometimes, you know, maybe there's a
report that's been open for a long time
and then it gets closed um
or, you know, they're doing cleanup or
whatever.
That can skew metrics quite a bit
because, you know, say you have some
4-year-old report that gets closed that
should have been closed, you know, years
ago and maybe it was fixed already and
just never got closed or something. That
can throw your metrics off
significantly. So, like you said, like
asking the team and just being like,
"Hey,
you know, it's been a couple months.
Just curious is any updates. And then
after it gets paid out, I I really see
no need in, you know, like you said,
understanding where the responsibilities
lie. It's the same thing for a security
team, right? Like it's not the security
team's job to go in and actually fix the
code. It's their job to support the team
who writes that code and tell them,
"Hey, here's the vulnerability. Here's
how you should go about fixing it."
Um, you know, like not on a code level,
but on a technical level, here's what
needs to change.
Um, and then letting the team engineer
that and verifying that it's fixed,
right? Like you don't want to be doing
everybody's job. Um, and and there are
certain roles and responsibilities for a
reason, so.
Yeah. What are some other things that,
well, not other, what are some things
that surprised you
uh after joining the the other side that
you would never sort of expect or
imagine just as as a bug bounty hunter?
Uh it's interesting cuz I've been on the
other side for so long now, um,
that it's it's hard to think about what
it was like when I was just a bug bounty
hunter, but I think um, a lot of it
boils down to just like the expectations
of getting stuff fixed like right away,
right? So, everybody thinks like, "Oh,
this is a security bug. Like
the engineering team is not doing
anything else." Like when they find out
that there's a security vulnerability,
like I just reported this. Like they're
going to drop everything and fix it. And
it's like, "No, like that is uh
in a perfect world, yeah, but um, like I
said, they they have their other stuff
going on. They have a a queue of other
engineering work that they were working
on for other features or other parts of
the product or other bugs. Um, not
necessarily security bugs, but just like
functionality
um, bugs and stuff like that that they
need to fix. And that stuff can have
higher priorities. They can have their
own deadlines, uh different projects and
stuff going on. So, it's a much more
complicated landscape behind the scenes
when you have multiple teams who are
also operating independently and doing
their own things.
Um, and then you sort of just throw like
a vulnerability in there and somehow it
has to get fixed. So, um, you know, it
in a like I said, in a perfect world,
yeah. It'd be great if when the security
team pulled up and said, "Hey, here's a
vulnerability.
Uh it's a medium." And they go, "Okay,
it'll be fixed tomorrow." Like you know,
maybe, but I think the the real way that
this works is that there's these things
called, um, you know, service level
agreements, SLAs. And basically that
just says, "We have this much time to
fix this." Um, I think there's SLAs on
HackerOne as well. Um, but, you know,
generally it just
you know, it gives them that buffer so
that if you report a vulnerability, they
have up to 2 weeks or up to however many
days um or hours or months or whatever
to fix it.
And if they fall out of that, then you
can start to, you know, from the
security team or whatever, you can say,
"Hey, you're past SLA. What's going on
with this? You know, this needs to be
fixed. You can't ignore it for this
long." Um,
but as the researcher, it's not your job
to know what those SLAs are and it's not
your your responsibility to, you know,
be pushing them from the outside uh to
get it fixed quicker. It's your job to
report the vulnerability and and get the
payout and that's it and find the next
bug. Yeah. If you were to create your
own bug bounty platform, would it be
very different from the ones that we
have like HackerOne, Bugcrowd, and
others?
Um,
um,
that's a good question. I think
generally it would be pretty similar.
Um,
like
one thing, and I don't want to diminish
away from the platforms too much here.
Like I think the platforms, if you boil
it down, are kind of like blurified
inboxes, to be honest. I mean, that is
what it is, right? Like um, even like
from the back end, like we refer to it
as like the the inbox, um,
where, you know, basically researchers
just have a a way to submit stuff to
you, and then you can, you know, it has
a lot of
feature-specific
functionality like, you know, severity
adjustments and CVSS calculation and
triage and all these these aspects that,
um, I think if you were to build it
yourself, it would be kind of difficult
unless you had a really, really
different process. And you see this with
the large companies like Microsoft and
stuff, they run their own um, platforms,
but um, most companies I think just it's
a convenience factor where having
something built in that's designed for
this, it's designed around this, that
has functionality and stuff that's
specific and bespoke for bug bounty and
bug
um, vulnerability research and all that
kind of stuff just makes it a lot
easier. Um, and then having the payouts
and stuff built in is is obviously
really, really helpful.
Yeah. Uh but also the reason I'm asking
this is I see you guys doing the the
Critical Thinking Bug Bounty podcast,
and I see you do really do already a lot
of things there, and I would not at all
be surprised if in a few years you would
become a really big company. And I would
not be surprised at all to see, you
know, Critical Thinking Bug Bounty
platform or what whatever would it be
called.
Yeah, yeah, we'll see. We'll see. Uh I
don't want to I don't want to spoil any
too much, but we yeah, we'll see what uh
what happens. I think we're definitely
trying to work um,
to to sort of expand the brand um, and
just sort of figure out what sort of
other stuff we can do with this audience
and and with this information that we
have.
Yeah. What what are some plans that you
can disclose to us?
Uh sure, yeah. So, um,
you know, like right now we're really
leaning into our Discord, I think. I I
think the community is really like the
the awesome part of the CTBB
podcast, um, where, you know, we have
all these really talented hackers are
constantly in the Discord like talking
about bugs, talking about, "Hey, I found
this thing. Any any idea on how I could
exploit it or how I could escalate this
further? Anybody have any experience
where you get your podcasts, um, you can
find me uh my personal socials
uh mostly it's just Twitter uh
twitter.com or X, I guess. x.com/ uh 0x
technogeek. That's with a K, t e k n o g
e e k. And um, yeah, on on Discord, I'm
just technogeek, same thing with a K.
Um, that's pretty much my username
everywhere uh for the most part. And um,
yeah, I just really appreciate And um,
good luck at your your upcoming live
hacking event. That's that sounds like
it's going to be awesome, man. Am I
going to see you there?
Yeah, I'll be in Vegas. Perfect.
Fantastic.
Awesome. Thanks so much for for joining
me, and see you then. All right. See you
then.
I feel like I could go on and on and on
for hours with Joe and still learn new
stuff every minute. But for today,
that's it. So, if you have learned
something new, please like this video.
And if you want to listen to another
episode of the podcast, check out this
one with Justin Gardner, the co-host of
the Critical Thinking Bug Bounty podcast
along with Joe. For now, thank you for
listening, and goodbye.